Gleason is a documentary film directed by J. Clay Tweel.
At the age of 34, former New Orleans Saints defensive back Steve Gleason was
diagnosed with ALS and given a life expectancy of two to five years.
Weeks later, Gleason found out his wife, Michel,
was expecting their first child.
A video journal that began as a gift for his unborn son expands to chronicle Steve’s determination to get his relationships in order, build a foundation to provide other
ALS patients with purpose, and adapt to his declining physical condition—utilizing medical technologies that offer the means to live as fully as possible.
Self, played by Steve Gleason.
Self, played by Michel Gleason.
Self, played by Rivers Gleason.
Self, played by Paul Varisco.
Self, played by Blair Casey.
Self, played by Scott Fujita.
Gleason is an American documentary film which
premiered at the 2016 Sundance Film Festival.
It covers five years in the life of the former New Orleans Saints football defensive back Steve Gleason, who has Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), sometimes known as Lou
Gehrig's disease, a rare incurable neurodegenerative condition associated with the former New York Yankees baseball star Lou Gehrig, who died from the disease in 1941.
The film explores themes of new orleans, louisiana, biography, saints,
nfl (national football league), new orleans saints.